## David Stewart

## **Professional Summary**

Quality-oriented professional with 10 years of experience and a proven knowledge of computer integrated manufacturing, work methods analysis, and research development practices. With a eye for quality. Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities.

## Work History

### Allied Automation - PROGRAMMER AND MACHINIST

Apex, NC

03/2020 - 06/2022

- Created complex multiple staged programs for high precision machining
- Maintained tight tolerances with design specifications.
- Used CNC and manual equipment to perform both initial and final machining.
- Studied work instruction, sketches, drawings, blueprints and manuals to determine dimensions and tolerances accurately.
- Obtained blueprints and materials from suppliers and engineers.
- Reduced run times and costs by implementing innovative and best practices. Reducing some programs runtimes by more than 50%.
- Manually set up machinery, vertical mills and grinders.

#### Griffin Motion - PROGRAMMER AND MACHINIST

Apex, NC

06/2018 - 03/2020

- Measure, examine, or test completed units to check for defects and ensure conformance to specifications, using precision instruments, such as micrometers.
- Study sample parts, blueprints, drawings, and engineering information to determine methods and sequences of operations needed to manufacture products, and determine product dimensions and tolerances.
- Confer with engineering, supervisory, or manufacturing personnel to exchange technical information.

✓ davidstew87@gmail.com

(919) 452-1260

**Q** Durham, NC 27713

## Website, Portfolio, Profiles

- https://dav3ster.github.io/The-Real-Deal/
- https://github.com/Dav3ster
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidstewart-8b046725a/

#### Skills

- JavaScript Programming
- Express Js
- Back-End and Database Skills
- Front-End Skills: HTML, CSS, React
- Version Control Systems: Git, GitHub
- Responsive Web Design
- Schematics Reading
- Design Specifications
- CAD Utilization

#### Education

Expected in 03/2023

## **UNC Chapel Hill**

Chapel Hill, NC

Certificate: Full Stack Web Development Currently enrolled at UNC Chapel Hill's full stack web development boot-camp. Learning to build full stack web

- Program CNC vertical mills using conversational (CAPS) software and HSM Express for solid works.
- Design fixtures, tooling, or experimental parts to meet special engineering needs.
- Evaluate experimental procedures, and recommend changes or modifications for improved efficiency and adaptability to setup and production.

# CA Foy Machine Co - CNC MACHINIST AND SHIFT MANAGER Kings Mountain, NC

04/2013 - 06/2018

- Calculate dimensions and tolerances using knowledge of mathematics and instruments such as micrometers and Vernier calipers.
- Align and secure holding fixtures, cutting tools, attachments, accessories, or materials onto machines.
- Set up, adjust, and operate all basic machine tools and many specialized or advanced variation tools to perform precision machining operations.
- Oversee activities directly related to making products or providing services.
- Manage staff, preparing work schedules and assigning specific duties.
- Trained and mentored new employees to maximize team performance.
- Maximized tooling speeds and feeds for best performance.

applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and other web tools such as Node, SQL, and Express.